# Sandy Chiu

I am a generalist product designer specialising in user experience design and visual design, coming from background of customer service, sales and marketing with keen interests in emerging technologies such as blockchain. I am experienced in working for enterprise clients in various industries including Finance, Insurance, and Retail.

London 07523121451 sandychiu.com hello@sandychiu.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Ensemble Systems, London — Designer & Developer

NOV 2016 - PRESENT

An Adobe solution partner who provide end-to-end software consulting services in Agile environment. I initially joined the internship program, then was promoted to junior and mid-weight role with responsibilities in leading design projects.

- Led UX design for clients and partners including Adobe, Puma, and Hitachi solutions.
- Communicated with stakeholders and cross-functional teams to iterate wireframes, prototypes, UI elements and handover for development.
- Collaborated projects across different time zones in North America and Europe.
- Supported CMS front-end development: Camelot Irish National Lottery and Illinois Lottery responsive websites, HSBC forms digitalisation portal.
- Redesigned and developed Ensemble UK website with improvements in performance.

## British Airways, London — Cabin Crew

NOV 2013 - NOV 2016

Contributed within international teams in a fast-paced environment, dedicated to resolve issues and handle emergencies calmly in stressful situations. Intensively trained to provide first aid and medical assistance on board, while delivering premium customer services.

## Mintel Market Research, London — Operational Executive

NOV 2012 - NOV 2013

Translated marketing content from Chinese to English, including websites, leaflets and packaging of prestige beauty products. Provided effective and accurate data resources of marketing research analysis, to offer insights for clients in Europe.

## **EDUCATION**

**Birkbeck**, London — MA in Digital Media Design

SEP 2018 - EXPECTED 2020

**Birkbeck,** London — PgCert in Web Design and Development (Merit)

SEP 2015 - JUN 2016

SEP 2003 - JUN 2007

**Fujen Catholic University,** Taipei — BA in Philosophy (Equivalent of 2:1)

### **SKILLS**

User flows, wireframing, prototyping, interaction design, HCI, user research, usability testing, design system, style guide, typography, colour theory, iconography, HTML, CSS (LESS/ SASS), JavaScript (Angular, React, jQuery), Bootstrap, responsive web design, accessibility.

#### **TOOLS**

Sketch, InVision, Zeplin, Balsamiq, Axure, Overflow, Adobe Creative Cloud apps (XD, Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator, After Effects), iMovie, Keynote, FileZilla, JIRA, Trello, GitHub, Git, Sourcetree, Sublime, Brackets, IntelliJ.

#### **INTERESTS**

Travelling, yoga, arts and crafts, illustration, reading, photography.